Profile:



Phone: +254-703-153-668

Email: sheerikie@gmail.com

Results-oriented software engineer and Online Business Developer with considerable training and enterprise experience in Web and mobile application development and in all stages of design, coding, and testing and in the formation, planning, and implementation of online business ventures.

Objective:

To excel as a software engineering expert through technical competence with an outlook on global emerging markets and technology.

Software Development Summary:

- Over five years of professional software and Web application development experience
- Highly Proficient with JavaScript, PHP and Laravel 5.
- Highly proficient in writing restful api and third party api communication
- Experience working with regular expressions
- CI/CD software engineer with agile methodology experience.
- MVC, designpatterns, Object-oriented Analysis and Design(OOAD), Docker Containerization, server deployment I.e AWS, heroku, google cloud platform, digital ocean and Git version control.
- Database Administration (oracle sql, mysql, mongodb, Redis, Pusher
- HTML, XHTML,SCSS and CSS, cross-browser compatible code and responsive code
- JavaScript and AJAX, including Vue js, angular js, angular 2+, Node js, react js, react native, Ionic Framework
- Web Services, SOAP, Restful Services, Atom, and RSS
- HTTP, TCP/IP, FTP, SMTP, and POP3
- SQL, MySQL, Postgresql, and Microsoft SQL Server
- Working experience with automated testing tools such as PHPUnit, Jest, Selenium, React Native Testing Library
- Proven Search Engine Optimization and Marketing (SEO/SEM) experience
- Excellent written and verbal communication skills
- Online business development and strategy
- Adobe XD, illustrator and a solid understanding of good website design

Education:

Kenyatta University
BSc. Software Engineering

2011-2016

Nairobi School

2007-2010

Adrian

Software Engineer

Work History:

Full-stack Developer

Oct 2021-present

Freelance Services:

responsible for ensuring the alignment of web design and user experience requirements, optimizing web pages for maximum efficiency and maintaining brand consistency across all web pages. Create APIs, integrate third party systems via APIs and build interfaces to access the value. Write well designed, testable and efficient codes. Lead design sprints and develop the use of cases from research and collected data. Applications done are available upon request.

Senior Developer Jan 2021-Oct 2021

Smartmile:

responsible for the development and improvement of the company's operational management application, This includes developing and implementing design plans, performing tests and code reviews I am also responsible for implementing CI/CD practices in software development . I also have to keep up with trends in software development and the industry in general and come up with ways to improve the current applications we have

Senior Developer 2020

LiteMore Ltd:

Was responsible for the development and improvement of the company's finance application, and now currently working on the e-learning solution, This includes developing and implementing design plans, performing tests and code reviews I am also responsible for implementing CI/CD practices in software development . I also have to keep up with trends in software development and the industry in general and come up with ways to improve the current applications we have.

Business Development

Senior Developer

AppEx Software Company

2018 - 2019

I was responsible for sourcing contracts from clients. Translating the client business requirements to technical requirements and implementing the requirements into a market ready software.

- Built custom software for clients and many informational and case-specific websites, web apps and mobile apps.
- Proficiency in CI/CD pipeline in initiating code builds, and deployment running automated tests
- Was responsible for full life-cycle application development and maintenance
- Used Photoshop, XD, XHTML, and CSS for all website design
- Used JavaScript and AJAX for all client-side scripting
- Utilized Redis to cache data and message brokerage
- Used PHP, and Java connected to SQLServer and MySQL for all server-side programming
- Utilized docker containerization and kubernates
- Utilized front-end development javascript frameworks to create interactive content i.e. react js, vue js, angular js to interact with backend endpoints.
- Native app mobile application development with React-Native

Senior Developer:

Zeiya ltd.

2017 - 2018

Responsible for the development of Internet sites and Intranet/Extranet system. Duties included, software design, programming, team management and optimization for search engine placement.

Full Stack Developer

AppEx Software Company

2013-2017

- Built custom software for clients and many informational and case-specific websites, web apps and mobile apps.
- Marketed websites through low-cost organic search engine optimization andlink building, gaining first page ranking onGoogle for many highly-competitive, high-traffic, targetedkeyword phrases
- Was responsible for full life-cycle application development and maintenance
- Used JavaScript and AJAX for all client-side scripting
- Used PHP, and Java connected to SQLServer and MySQL for all server-side programming